export var questions = [
  {
    question: "Which method(s) of heat transfer can take place in vacuum?",
    options: ["Conduction", "Convection", "Radiation", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Radiation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which electromagnetic radiation transmits the highest photon energy?",
    options: [
      "Infrared rays",
      "Microwaves",
      "Ultraviolet radiations",
      "Gamma rays",
    ],
    answer: "Gamma rays",
  },
  {
    question: "Greenhouse gases absorb ________ radiation.",
    options: ["infrared", "microwaves", "ultraviolet", "gamma"],
    answer: "infrared",
  },

  {
    question: "100mL is equal to",
    options: ["1kL", "10-6 µL", "0.1 L", "0.01 ML"],
    answer: "0.1 L",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The linear momentum of a particle is the product of its mass and its velocity. Consequently, the SI units of linear momentum",
    options: ["Kg/ (m/s)", "Kg · m · s", "kg · m/s", "None of these"],
    answer: "kg · m/s",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Newton’s law of gravitation is an inverse-square law. When separated by a distance d, two unlike charges exert mutual attractive forces of magnitude F on each other. If the separation distance between these charges are doubled, how strong are the mutual forces now?",
    options: ["F/4", "F/2", "2F", "4F"],
    answer: "F/4",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An astronaut weighs 80N on earth where the acceleration due to gravity is approximately 10 m/s2. The mass of the astronaut at a point in space where the acceleration due to gravity is 4 m/s2 is roughly",
    options: ["80 kg", "32 kg", "20 kg", "8 kg"],
    answer: "8 kg",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Copper is a better conductor than paper. Relative to the resistance of a sample of copper, the resistance of an identically shaped sample of paper is",
    options: ["Larger", "The same", "Smaller", "None of these"],
    answer: "Larger",
  },
  {
    question: "If an object has a constant velocity, then it:",
    options: [
      "Moves with unchanging speed in a straight line.",
      "Moves with unchanging speed along a circle.",
      "Does not move at all.",
      "Either A or C.",
    ],
    answer: "Moves with unchanging speed in a straight line.",
  },
  {
    question: "The SI prefix ‘milli’ means",
    options: ["10^-6", "10^+3", "10^-3", "10^+6"],
    answer: "10^-3",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not an SI base quantity?",
    options: ["Length", "Mass", "Weight", "Time"],
    answer: "Weight",
  },
  {
    question: "The unit of mass in the SI system",
    options: ["Pound", "Gram", "Kilogram", "None of these"],
    answer: "Kilogram",
  },
  {
    question: "The metric prefix for 1/1000",
    options: ["Centi", "Kilo", "Micro", "None of these"],
    answer: "None of these",
  },
  {
    question: "One milliliter is equal to one",
    options: [
      "Cubic decimeter",
      "Cubic centimeter",
      "Cubic meter",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Cubic centimeter",
  },
  {
    question: "In terms of fundamental SI units, one newton is",
    options: [
      "1 kg · m^2/s^2",
      "1 kg · m^2/s",
      "1 kg · m/s^2",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "1 kg · m/s^2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Two charged particles attract each other with a force of 1.0 N. If the magnitude of each charge is doubled and the distance between them is unchanged, the force will be",
    options: ["4.0 N", "0.5 N", "1.0 N", "0.25 N"],
    answer: "4.0 N",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following bodies has the largest kinetic energy?",
    options: [
      "Mass 2M with speed 3V",
      "Mass 3M with speed 2V",
      "Mass M with speed 4V",
      "Mass 3M with speed V",
    ],
    answer: "Mass 2M with speed 3V",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When an object thrown vertically upwards reaches its maximum height, it has",
    options: [
      "Zero acceleration and zero velocity",
      "Zero acceleration and negative velocity",
      "Negative acceleration and zero velocity",
      "Negative acceleration and negative velocity",
    ],
    answer: "Negative acceleration and zero velocity",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A battery of 3.0 V is placed across a wire of a 5.0 W lamp. The resulting current in the wire is",
    options: ["0.60 A", "15 A", "60 A", "125 A"],
    answer: "0.60 A",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An object attached to one end of a spring makes 20 vibrations in 10 seconds. The period of the object is",
    options: ["2 Hz", "2 seconds", "0.5 seconds", "0.5 Hz"],
    answer: "2 Hz",
  },
  {
    question: "How many nanometers are there in one meter?",
    options: ["10^-9", "10^+3", "10^-3", "10^+9"],
    answer: "10^+9",
  },
  {
    question: "A kilowatt-hour is a unit of:",
    options: ["Time", "Power", "Energy", "Voltage"],
    answer: "Energy",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following has three significant figures?",
    options: ["305.0 cm", "1.00081 kg", "0.0500 mm", "8.060 x 1011 m^2"],
    answer: "0.0500 mm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An apple falls from a tree. Compare its kinetic energy, K, to its potential energy, U.",
    options: [
      "K decreases and U decreases",
      "K is constant and U increases",
      "K increases and U decreases",
      "K increases and U is constant",
    ],
    answer: "K increases and U decreases",
  },
  {
    question: "The resistance of an object to changes in motion",
    options: ["Acceleration", "Density", "Inertia", "None of these"],
    answer: "Inertia",
  },
  {
    question: "The amount of space an object takes up",
    options: ["Density", "Speed", "Mass", "None of these"],
    answer: "None of these",
  },
  {
    question: "Distance traveled in a period of time",
    options: ["Motion", "Acceleration", "Speed", "None of these"],
    answer: "None of these",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of these is the independent variable in a distance-time graph",
    options: ["Time", "Distance", "Speed", "None of these"],
    answer: "Time",
  },
  {
    question: "The term normally used to indicate a decrease in speed",
    options: ["Acceleration", "Deceleration", "Stop", "None of these"],
    answer: "Deceleration",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is an example of a simple machine ?",
    options: ["Whistle", "Battery", "Typewriter", "Lever"],
    answer: "Lever",
  },
  {
    question: "The number of significant figures in 0.40 is",
    options: ["One", "Two", "Three", "Four"],
    answer: "Two",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following simple machines would be most closely related to the screw ?",
    options: ["Wheel and axle", "Inclined plane", "Pulley", "Lever"],
    answer: "Inclined plane",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To push a car 30 meters in 20 seconds takes approximately 4,500 joules of work. How much power is needed in joules per second ?",
    options: ["0.25", "225.00", "1,500.00", "7,500.00"],
    answer: "225.00",
  },
  {
    question: "A mercury barometer",
    options: [
      "Is a closed tube manometer",
      "Is an open tube manometer",
      "Is usually 760. cm tall",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Is a closed tube manometer",
  },
  {
    question: "Forces that are opposite in direction and equal in size",
    options: ["Balanced", "Unbalanced", "Imaginary", "None of these"],
    answer: "Balanced",
  },
  {
    question: "A force acting through a distance is called",
    options: ["Work", "Acceleration", "Power", "None of these"],
    answer: "Work",
  },
  {
    question: "Newtons are the units of",
    options: ["Power", "Work", "Weight", "None of these"],
    answer: "Weight",
  },
  {
    question: "The energy associated with charged particles",
    options: ["Electricity", "Light", "Atoms", "None of these"],
    answer: "Electricity",
  },
  {
    question: "This type of electric current flows in only one direction",
    options: [
      "Alternating current",
      "Static",
      "Static electricity",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "None of these",
  },
  {
    question: "This type of current is produced by a battery",
    options: [
      "Alternating current",
      "Direct current",
      "Static electricity",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Direct current",
  },
  {
    question: "Materials that easily allow the flow of an electric current",
    options: ["Resistors", "Conductors", "Semiconductors", "None of these"],
    answer: "Conductors",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of these in not an emergency switch in an electric circuit",
    options: ["Fuse", "Circuit breaker", "Transistor", "None of these"],
    answer: "Transistor",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A change in the pitch of a sound due to the motion of either the sound source or the observer",
    options: ["Resonance", "Reverberation", "Refraction", "None of these"],
    answer: "None of these",
  },
];
